Guide to the William Saroyan Papers, 1926-1981
Department of Special Collections
William Saroyan Papers,
1926-1981
Special Collections M0870
Saroyan, William, 1908-1981
185 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Manuscripts, correspondence, journals, drawings, scrapbooks, clippings, financial and legal records, his personal typewriter, and ephemera.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Saroyan Foundation
Biography
Novelist, short-story writer, dramatist, and essayist, William Saroyan was born in Fresno, California in 1908. A high-school dropout, Saroyan was largely self-educated and decided at an early age to pursue a career as a writer, drawing on his experience as an Armenian-American growing up in California.
His first published works were sketches in The Overland Monthly in 1928, which inspired him to seek his fortune in New York City. In 1934 Story Magazine printed "The Daring Young Man on the Flying Trapeze." The immediate public acclaim led to publication of the collection The Daring Young Man on the Flying Trapeze and Other Stories (1934) by Random House. He followed this success with two more short story collections in 1936, Three Times Three and Inhale and Exhale.
Transforming one of these stories into his first dramatic production, My Heart's in the Highlands (1939), Saroyan then wrote The Time of Your Life (1939-40), for which he received both New York Drama Critics' Circle Award and the Pulitzer Prize. The same year he released the story collection, My Name is Aram (1940), a Book of the Month Club selection.
In late 1941 Saroyan agreed to work for Louis B. Mayer in Hollywood. This resulted both in the Oscar-winning MGM film, The Human Comedy, (1943) as well as the popular novelized version of the original screenplay, published by Harcourt Brace simultaneously with the movie's opening.
Drafted into the army, Saroyan was stationed during part of World War II in London, where he wrote the controversial anti-war book, The Adventures of Wesley Jackson (1946). Through the 1950s he continued to produce plays, short stories, and novels. He then turned to personal memoirs to express himself, producing in succession The Bicycle Rider in Beverly Hills (1952), Here Comes, There Goes, You Know Who (1961), Not Dying (1963), and Obituaries (1980), which was nominated for the American Book Award. A final volume of reminiscence, Births (1983), was published posthumously.
Scope and Content
Saroyan's papers document his personal and professional life and include manuscripts, correspondence, journals, drawings, scrapbooks, clippings, financial and legal records, and ephemera. The correspondence, which includes both incoming and outgoing items, is with his family, publishers, fans, agents, attorneys, writers, actors, and other public figures. The manuscripts include novels, plays, short stories, memoirs, essays, poems and music. The scrapbooks date from 1935 to 1942 and contain clippings, programs, and photos relating to some of Saroyan's first theatrical productions.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
American literature--20th century.
Genres and Forms of Material
Typewriters.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, ca. 1926-1981, Series 1
  Correspondence in the collection covers the years 1926-1981, with the bulk falling in the years after 1950. Major correspondents include family members, attorneys, agents, and publishers. Also included are notable literary, stage and film figures such as Charley Chaplin and Oona O'Neill, John Houseman, Darryl F. Zanuck, George Jean Nathan, Garson Kanin, and composers Joaquin Rodrigo and Alan Hovhaness. From the 1950s on, Saroyan kept carbon copies of most of his correspondence, which he attached to letters incoming from others. Approximately one quarter of all correspondence is from William Saroyan himself. Saroyan occasionally used the pseudonym "Aram Garoghlanian" for magazine subscriptions and it may appear on other correspondence as well.
  - A miscellany, 1.01
    - AAA - Abromson (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academy - Actors (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adair - A.D.W. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Afro - Aistrop (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ajderian - Aktiebolaget (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alameda - Altounian (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Amateur - American Brotherhood (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Center - American Community (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - American Druggist - American Legion (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - American Museum - American Productions (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - American Reader - American Visitors (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Americana - Amphoto (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Anaheim - Anvil (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - A-1 - Aquarian (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Arabian - Arlington (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Armenian A - Armenian Literary (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Armenian Mesrobian - Armenian National (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Armenian Presbyterian - Armenian Youth (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Armstrong - Artesian (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Arthur - Arzoomanian (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Asahi - Astoorian (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - At - Attaway (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Auchincloss - Autzen (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Avak - Aviz (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Axmann - Azrouni (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A primary, 1.02
    - American Academy of Arts Letters
      See: National Institute of Arts Letters
    - Atlantic Monthly Press
      See also: Lawrence, Seymour
    - Alioto, Joseph,1973-74, 7 items: 2 from WS (Folder 14)
    - Abbott, George,1954, 16 items: 8 from WS (Box 4, Folder 1)
      See also: Ah, San Francisco
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences,1946-76, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Acting Company,1975-76, 8 items: 1 from WS (Box 4, Folder 3)
      See also: Houseman, John
    - Adamic, Louis,1939-40, 2 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Addison-Wesley Publishing Co.,.1968-70, 23 items: 8 from WS (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Adler, Luther,1947-54, 19 items: 12 from WS (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Aharonian, Varkes,1939-58, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Adler, Stella,1975-76, 4 items: 1 from WS (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ahlstrom, David,1980, 3 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Albee, Edward,1979-80, 2 items: 1 from WS (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Alevy, Maurice,1954-58, 37 items: 5 from WS (Box 4, Folder 11)
      See also: Round-Up Theater
    - Alexa, Joseph,1951-53, 7 items: 5 from WS (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Algren, Nelson,1951, 1 item from WS (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Allen, Corey,1958, 3 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - ALMO ,1959-75, 9 items: 3 from WS (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Alperin, Philip,1952-53, 9 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - American Broadcasting Corp.,1948-53, 3 items: 1 from WS (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - American Conservatory Theatre,1966-74, 4 items: 4 from WS (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - American Federation of Television And Radio Artists,1955-76, 19 items: 1 from WS (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - American Heritage Publishing Co.,1980, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - American Library in Paris,1946; 1974, 4 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - American Magazine,1941-56, 9 items: 4 from WS (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - American Mercury,1934-57, 38 items: 6 from WS (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - American Name Society,1953-57, 20 items: 5 from WS (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - American University of Beirut,1972-75, 8 items to WS (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Amirian, Lemyel1935-74, 37 items: 7 from WS (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Amirian, Lemyel1976-79, 16 items: 3 from WS (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Anderson, Sherwood,1936, 1 item to WS (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Angelo, Valenti,1936-1950, 9 items: 3 from WS (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Aperatif,1936, 1 item from WS (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Appel, Ben,1934-77, 19 items to WS (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ararat,1960-80, 44 items: 8 from WS (Box 5, Folder 5)
      See also: Kherdian, Dave; Hamalian, Leo
    - Arax, Aram,1949-78, 9 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Argosy,1954-57, 17 items: 6 from WS (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Argus Book Shop,1934-39, 26 items to WS (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Arlen, Harold,1955, 3 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Armen, Kay,1962, 2 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Armenian Assembly,1976-78, 8 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Armenian General Benevolent Union1935-74, 37 items: 4 from WS (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Armenian General Benevolent Union1975-80, 25 items: 3 from WS (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Armenian Mirror-Spectator,1957-60, 5 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Armenian Reporter,1971-78, 5 items to WS (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Armenian Review,1959-78, 32 items: 10 from WS (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Armenian Spectator,1934-36, 7 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Armenian Weekly,1970-77, 6 items: 3 from WS (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Arno Press,1970-79, 8 items to WS (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Arthur, Jean,1955, 2 items: 1 from WS (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Artijus,1962-78, 18 items: 3 from WS (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Associated Educational Services.1967-69, 18 items: 3 from WS (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Associated Press,1942-81, 11 items: 4 from WS (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Atamian, Krikor,1961-80, 50 items: 16 from WS (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1965-66, 14 items: 3 from WS (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1967 Jan.-May, 21 items: 1 from WS (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1967 June-Dec., 22 items: 6 from WS (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1968, 27 items: 12 from WS (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1969-70, 13 items: 1 from WS (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1972-73, 20 items: 10 from WS (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1974, 23 items: 7 from WS (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1975 Jan.-July, 21 items: 4 from WS (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1975 Aug.-Dec., 25 items: 6 from WS (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1976, 18 items: 8 from WS (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1977, 14 items: 3 from WS (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1978, 19 items: 4 from WS (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1979, 15 items to WS (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1980, 6 items: 3 from WS (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Athearn, Chandler Hoffman1981, 6 items: 2 from WS (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press1939-55, 55 items: 21 from WS (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press1956, 77 items: 26 from WS (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press1957-61, 55 items: 22 from WS (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press1962-71, 52 items: 18 from WS (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Atlantic Monthly Press1972-79, 34 items: 10 from WS (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Authors' Agency Ltd.,1966-76, 9 items: 1 from WS (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Author's Guild,1939-72, See also: Author's League of America (Box 8, Folder 7)
      10 items to WS
    - Author's League of America,1939-81, See also: Author's Guild; Dramatists Guild (Box 8, Folder 8)
      34 items: 6 from WS
    - Avakian, Anne,1934-80, 11 items: 3 from WS (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Avakian, George,1949-79, See also: Columbia Records (Box 8, Folder 10)
      17 items: 5 from WS
    - Avery, Val,1974, 7 items: 3 from WS (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Avon Book Co.,1946-61, 16 items: 3 from WS (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - B miscellany, 1.03
    - Babayan - Baird (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bais - Balch (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Baldwin - Banta (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Banter - Baronian (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Barr - Basic (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Basil - BC (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Beacham - Beckman (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bedford - Beloin (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Bemidji - Beruh (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Beshar - BFL (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Bibas - Bissiri (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Black - Blum's (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - B'Nai - B'Nai B'Rith Women (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Boal - Bois (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Bokforlaget - Bonosky (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Book - Bookman (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Books - Boston University (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bostonian - Boyajian (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Boyer - Bozart (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Bradford - Brevard (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bridge - Bromberg (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn - Browne (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Browning - Bryn (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Buchanan - Butler (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Byrd - Byron (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - B primary, 1.04
    - Bohnert, McCarthy, Flowers, Roberts Damir
      See: Damir, Robert
    - Borzoi Books
      See: Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
    - Babb, Sanora,1932-41; n.d., 49 items: 3 from WS (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Badal, Angelique,1977, 15 items: 4 from WS (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Badlian, Richard,1934; 1936, 3 items to WS (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bagdasarian, Ross1938-52, 52 items: 16 from WS (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bagdasarian, Ross1953-62; n.d., 42 items: 17 from WS (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bagdasarian, Dick,1947; 1962, 4 items: 3 from WS (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bailey, F. Lee,1972, 3 items: 1 from WS (Box 11, Folder 7)
      See also: Gallery
    - Bakjian, Andy,1975, 4 items: 1 from WS (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Bakjian, Mardie,1934-61, 46 items to WS (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Balakian, Anna,1974; 1980, 2 items to WS (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Balakian, Nona1973-75, 23 items: 8 from WS (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Balakian, Nona1976, 26 items: 12 from WS (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Balakian, Nona1977-80; n.d., 56 items: 21 from WS (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Ballantine Books Inc.,1953-71; n.d., 25 items: 6 from WS (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Bancroft Library1955-76, 38 items: 6 from WS (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - The Bancroft Library1977-81, 40 items: 9 from WS (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Banklian, Armen,1958-73; n.d., 25 items: 2 from WS (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Bantam Books1947-65, 32 items: 9 from WS (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Bantam Books1966-80, 24 items: 7 from WS (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bar. David Literary Agency,1969-78, 19 items: 4 from WS (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Barash, Stanley,1941-57, 20 items: 9 from WS (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Bardizian, Armen,1933-51, 8 items to WS (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Barooshian, Stephen,1976-77, 10 items: 2 from WS (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Barr, Richard,1955-60, 9 items: 3 from WS (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Barry, Joe,1975-76, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Hans Bartsch Plays,1945-47, 7 items: 3 from WS (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Basmadjian, Garig,1974-77, 12 items: 3 from WS (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Bayerische Ruckversicherung Aktiengesellschaft,1975; n.d., 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bayliss, John,1965, 9 items: 4 from WS (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Beacon Press,1969-70, 8 items: 3 from WS (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Beeson, Jack,1953-70; n.d., 40 items: 13 from WS (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Behavioral Science Associates,1967-68, 13 items: 4 from WS (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bekins Movers,1959-80, 13 items: 4 from WS (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bel Geddes, Barbara,1954, 5 items: 1 from WS (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Belwin Mills Publishing Corp.,1970-81, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Bender, Albert,1936; 1939, 6 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Berger, Mark,1955, 2 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Bergman, Frank,1933-34; n.d., 3 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Berkeley Repertory Theater,1980, 4 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 8)
      See also: David, Narsai
    - Bettis, Valerie,1971-73, 10 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Bezzerides, Al,1934-39, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Blake, Robert,1948, 7 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Bode, Carl,1974-75, 2 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bodek, Gordon,1979-80, 7 items: 1 from WS (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Bogdanovich, Peter,1960, 2 items: 1 from WS (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Bond, Anson and King Vidor,1951, 5 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Albert Bonnier Publishing House,1942-46, 5 items: 1 from WS (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Bontemps, Arna,1951, 1 item to WS (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Book Collector's Journal,1936, 6 items to WS (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club,1941-77; n.d., 15 items: 3 from WS (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Books for Libraries,1970-79, 15 items: 3 from WS (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Boston University Journal,1974, 10 items: 3 from WS (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Bowles, Paulm1979, 1 item to WS (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Boyle, Kay,1934-58, 15 items: 2 from WS (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Boy's Life,1955-72, 26 items: 8 from WS (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Bradbury, Ray,1951, 1 item from WS (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Brandt Brandt,1950-58, 19 items: 6 from WS (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - George Braziller, Inc.1957-60, 25 items; 7 from WS (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - George Braziller, Inc.1961-78; n.d., 25 items: 7 from WS (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Brigham Young University,1970-71, 10 items: 2 from WS (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Britton, Burt,1974-75, 6 items: 3 from WS (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Broadcast Music Inc.,1951-65, 14 items: 4 from WS (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Bromberg, J. Edward,1942, 3 items from WS (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Brooks, Bill,1961, 1 item to WS (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Broun's Nutmeg,1939, 6 items to WS (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd.,1947; 1961-64, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew,1972-75, 14 items: 3 from WS (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Bryant, Markham,1947-48, 13 items: 9 from WS (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Buchwald, Art,1958-59, 4 items: 1 from WS (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Bufano, Beniamino,1939-69; n.d., 8 items to WS (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Bulgaria (Embassy),1977-80, 13 items: 4 from WS (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Burke, Sonny,1951, 3 items from WS (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Leo Burnett Co., Inc.,1973, 2 items to WS (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Burnett, Whit,1952-70, 13 items: 5 from WS (Box 14, Folder 17)
      See also: Story
    - Buttons, Red,1957, 1 item to WS (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - C miscellany, 1.05
    - Caddie - Calhoun (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - California A - California P (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - California Shakespeare - Call (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Callahan - Canadian G (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Canale - Caramanian (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Cardinal - Carr (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Carre - Cassal (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Cassell - Cavoukian (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - CDN - Cezanne (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Chaffee - Chazin (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Chekhov - Chicago Herald (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Chicago Sun - Chozlian (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Chris - Chvokoron (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Cincinnati - Civil (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Claire - Clark (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Clarke - Clough (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - CMA - Cohn (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Colbert - Collins (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Colonial - Columbia Univ. Press (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Columbus - Comparative (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Conaway - Conte (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Contemporanul - Cooper (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Cope - Council (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Country - C.P. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Crabtree - Crawford (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Creative - Cricket (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Crispino - Crush (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Cub - Czebotar (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - C primary, 1.06
    - Cerf, Bennett
      See: Random House, Inc.
    - City Center Theatre
      See: Dalrymple, Jean
    - Caedmon Records,1961-71; n.d., 20 items: 5 from WS (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Caen, Herb,1939-81; n.d., 35 items: 11 from WS (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cagney Productions,1934-48, 52 items: 23 from WS (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Calif. Dental Assoc. Journal,1976, 6 items: 1 from WS (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - California. Dept. of Motor Vehicles,1951-56, 6 items to WS (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - California. Dept. of Veterans Affairs,1964; n.d., 8 items to WS (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - California State Automobile Assn.,1947-73; n.d., 9 items: 3 from WS (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - California State Univ., Fresno,1946-80, 43 items: 6 from WS (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - California State Univ., Northridge,1977-81, 31 items: 12 from WS (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Univ. of California, Berkeley,1939-79, 13 items: 3 from WS (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Univ. of California, Los Angeles,1948-75, 22 items: 5 from WS (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Calonne, David and Marion,1980, 3 items to WS (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corp.,1953-77, 30 items: 8 from WS (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Canadian National Institute for the Blind, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Cannon, Jimmy,1956, 3 items: 1 from WS (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Capa, Cornell,1968-70, 4 items: 1 from WS (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Capitol Records,1951, 9 items: 1 from WS (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Capp, Al,1950, 2 items from WS (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Carmen Capalbo and Stanley Chase,1955-58, 37 items: 17 from WS (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Carradine, John,1947, 1 item from WS (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Jimmy,1977, 3 items: 2 from WS (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Cassell and Company,1952-71, 20 items: 6 from WS (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Cavalier,1956-71, 51 items: 16 from WS (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Center Theater Group,1967-76; n.d., 12 items: 5 from WS (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Jacques Chambrun, Inc.,1946-58; n.d., 50 items: 12 from WS (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Chaplin, Charlie and Oona O'Neill,1947-51; n.d., 8 items: 5 from WS (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Chappell Co., Inc.,1951, 7 items: 4 from WS (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Chavoor, Frank,1971-73, 6 items: 1 from WS (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Chekhov Theatre Studio,1939-42; n.d., 11 items: 3 from WS (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Childress, William,1973-81; n.d., 37 items; 8 from WS (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Chilton Book Co.,1970, 5 items: 2 from WS (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Chisholm, Alex ,1971-79, 7 items to WS (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Christian Science Monitor,1957; 1975-79, 28 items: 10 from WS (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Circle Players,1947-48, 16 items: 8 from WS (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Clarke, Irwin Co.,1969-71, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Clemens, Cyril1935-72, 39 items: 2 from WS (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Clemens, Cyril1973-81; n.d., 28 items to WS (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Clooney, Rosemary,1951, 1 item from WS (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Clurman, Harold,1951; 1971, 5 items: 2 from WS (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - The Coast,1938-39; n.d., 11 items: 2 from WS (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Coates, Grace,1934; 1936, 11 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Cohen, Les,1949, 2 items: 1 from WS (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Cohn, Art,1958, 2 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - College Humor,1936; 1939, 6 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Collier, Peter,1972, 2 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Collier Books,1962-63, 9 items: 2 from WS (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Colliers,1938-56, 32 items: 11 from WS (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Collins Associates,1973, 4 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System (Radio),1951-61, 7 items: 1 from WS (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System (Television)1936-53, 62 items: 23 from WS (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System (Television)1954-78; n.d., 64 items: 19 from WS (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Columbia Pictures,1936-55, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Columbia Records1941-54, 65 items: 27 from WS (Box 19, Folder 16)
      See also: Avakian, George
    - Columbia Records1955-65; n.d., 61 items: 19 from WS (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Columbia University,1947-80; n.d., 6 items to WS (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Committee for Cultural Relations with Armenians Abroad,1970-81, 39 items: 8 from WS (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Comstock Editions,1971, 8 items: 3 from WS (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Conrad, Barnaby,1954-80, 8 items: 2 from WS (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Contact,1958, 10 items: 4 from WS (Box 20, Folder 4)